Pretty much all the robots we're interested in for this course,
在本课程中 我们感兴趣的机器人
share the same basic characteristics.
几乎都具备相同的特征
They contain sensors for perceiving the world around them,
它们都包括传感器 可以感知周边的世界
software for making high level decisions,
通过软件进行高层决策
and motors and controllers for actuation.
并利用马达和控制器驱动
ROS provides a powerful communications system
ROS 提供了强劲的通信系统
allowing these different components to communicate with one another.
允许不同组件互相沟通
Here, we'll introduce this communication system by considering a generic robot.
这里 我们以通用机器人为例 介绍这个通信系统
This robot could be a drone,
机器人可能是无人机
a mobile base or even a robotic arm.
移动底座甚至机器手臂
While these robots may be composed of very different physical components,
尽管这些机器人可能由非常不同的物理组件构成
they are all built to perform these same three high level steps of perception,
它们从构造上来说 都可以执行三个大致步骤：感知
decision making and actuation.
决策和驱动
On the software side,
从软件侧来说
ROS manages these three complex steps by breaking
ROS 管理这三个复杂的步骤时
each of them down into many small unit processes called nodes.
将每个分解为很多更小的单元流程 我们称之为节点
Typically, each node on the system is responsible for
通常 系统上的每个节点负责
one small and relatively specific portion of the robot's overall functionality.
机器人功能总体的一个特定的小部分
For example, there may be nodes for each sensor and actuator in the system,
例如 系统中可能每个传感器都有相应节点
as well as nodes for things like position estimation,
此外还有节点对应位置估算
behavior execution and motor control.
行为执行和马达控制
At the center of this collection of nodes is
在这些节点的中心
the ROS Master which acts as a sort of manager of all the nodes.
是 ROS 主进程 它相当于所有节点的管理器
The ROS Master maintains a registry of all the active nodes on a system.
ROS 主进程维护着系统上所有节点的注册表
It then allows each node to discover other nodes in
它允许每个节点发现系统里的其他节点
the system and establish lines of communication with them.
并与其建立通信线路
In addition to allowing nodes to locate one another and communicate,
除了允许节点相互发现和通信外
the ROS Master also hosts what's called the parameter server.
ROS 主进程还负责作为参数服务器
As its name suggests,
如其名称所示
the parameter server is typically used to store parameters
参数服务器通常用于存储参数
and configuration values that are shared amongst the running nodes.
和配置值 并在运行节点中共享
For example, a mobile robot's wheel radius may be used by
例如 一台移动机器人的轮子半径
one node to estimate position and by another to calculate speed.
可能被一个节点用于位置估算 同时被另一个节点用于速度计算
Rather than storing the same information in multiple places,
节点不会在多个地点存储相同信息
nodes can look up values as needed.
它会按需检索信息
Nodes can also share data with one
节点也可以相互共享数据
another by passing messages over what are called topics.
通过在主题上相互传递信息实现这一功能
A topic is simply a named bus which you can think of as
主题是一个命名的信息传输通路 可以看做
a pipe between nodes through which messages flow.
节点之间传递消息的管道
In order to send a message on a topic,
要在一个主题上发送消息
we say that a node must publish to it.
节点必须把消息发布到该主题
Likewise, to receive a message on a topic,
同样地 要从一个主题接收消息
a node must subscribe to it.
节点必须订阅该主题
Here's an example of the topics,
这个例子说明了
publishers and subscribers for the nodes we introduced earlier.
我们之前介绍过的主题、发布者和订阅者
The arrows represent message flow from publishers to subscribers.
箭头代表从发布者到订阅者的消息流
It's important to note that each node may
值得注意的是 每个节点都可能
simultaneously publish and subscribe to a wide variety of topics.
同步发布并订阅大量不同主题
Taken together, this network of nodes connected by topics is
合在一起 这个节点网络通过主题连接
called publish subscribe or a pub sub architecture.
我们称之为发布订阅架构或 pub/sub 架构